This first guy that I met, local guy,
he gets a $200,000 check while I'm sitting there.
Flips it around, he says, hey, you'll get there
one day. My mind was just blown. I was actually
working at Papa John's delivering pizza. And
I literally remember getting that first call while
I was straight up mopping the floor. Dropped the
mop, take the call, ended up closing. I made $7,000.
Welcome back, guys, to another episode of
10 Questions with Millionaires. I'm sitting here
with Matt Teifke, owner of Teifke Real Estate. Him
and his partners have a goal to make the most
entrepreneurial real estate brokerage on the
planet. Thanks for coming on, Matt.
Yeah, man. Thanks for the intro. I'm really excited
to be here. I love seeing what you guys do.
And that's right. That is the goal.
We're very driven and motivated by that and
couldn't be more excited about the future.
I love it. I love it. And if you
wouldn't mind, just give us a little introduction to yourself,
maybe a little bit of your story, where you're
from and what you kind of do on a day-to-day
and what brought us to this moment here.
Yeah, man. Absolutely. So born
in Cleveland, Ohio, right here.
Moved to Austin when I was two and a half.
Two and a half years old and grew up
single mom, brother, who ended up going to the Marines.
My mom really inspired me on showing what's
possible with real estate. So I got started
at 17 years old. I went to Texas A&M
Corpus Christi, Islanders, baby. And that was a great
experience. I got my license when I was 17 years
old and I started at a mom and pop brokerage.
First one in, last one out, just hustling, man. I
got rookie of the year. I was a full-time student.
I was going to class
and could care less about class.
Wait to get out and do some deals.
So that was great. Had a mentor, graduated,
worked for a commercial brokerage in Round
Rock until I got accepted to Texas A&M.
And I went and got my master's degree
in real estate, which was all financial based.
Worked at an apartment, got an appraisal
license. And I always wanted to learn as
much as possible about real estate and then
figure out how do I own real estate.
Started a company right when
I graduated school with my wife.
We built up to 700 doors
that we were managing, third-party management.
We ended up selling that company two years ago
and then teamed up with a longtime childhood friend,
Alex Kaufman, AKA Coffee Black, true
brother. And we built an entrepreneurial brokerage.
That's amazing. You got a lot going on. And I
heard that you mentioned that you did go to college.
I do want to ask, do you think
that that experience of going to college has
been transferable in your skills today as owning
a real estate brokerage and going out and finding
deals? And in addition to that, do
you think that that is necessary for success?
In society?
Necessary? No. It is what you make it. Just like
anything, right? And so I teach a class now in
college, which is really cool. But I told the
students yesterday, hey, all of you guys in this
room right now have a lot of ways to help
each other out. And most people just don't go all in
on that, right? Like you got 10 students there
that are all interested in business. What can you 10
people do together for the rest of your life? So
many things. But most people maybe just show up to
class and leave.
Yeah.
So it is what you make it.
Yeah, that's great. And I do want to take
back, you had mentioned earlier in kind of your intro,
kind of how you got started in real estate.
Maybe take us back there, dive a little bit
more in the details of how you kind of
got linked up into your first involvement in real estate.
And also, what was your first deal or maybe not
even first deal, but the first way that you made
money in real estate?
What I didn't realize at the time was
almost every brokerage wants new agents, right? So I
set up my interviews. I had a place
called Guarandine. I had Kelly Williams. I had,
I had Coldwell Bankers. I show up in a
suit and tie. I'm interviewing because I want this job,
right? It's the other way around. But I didn't
know that. Like the brokers want you, but I'm like
hoping that they'll give me the job, right? So I
go and I'm not kidding. This first guy that I met,
local guy, he just passed away a week and a
half ago. He gets a $200,000 check while I'm sitting
there. And like she brings it into him and
he flips it around. He says, hey, you'll get there
one day. My mind was just blown, right?
Oh, that's so motivating.
Dude. And he's like, you'll get there one day. So
he said, you got the job. And I canceled the
other interviews. You know, I just was like, hell yeah,
I got the job. Let's go. And that's when I
took that opportunity. And I was actually working
at Papa John delivering pizza while I was working
at the brokerage because I needed to make
money. Right. And I literally remember getting that first
call while I was straight up mopping the floor. Wow.
Drop the mop, take the call.
Ended up closing. I made $7,000 or $6,000. And it
blew my mind because at the time I was getting,
you know, $600 checks.
I was going to say that's got to
be way more than what you were bringing in.
Way more. I've never seen a check like that,
right? Even growing up, maybe full time I'd get
like $1,500 or $2,000, right? And so $6,000 one
time going to the bank, it blew my mind.
And I was hooked.
That was your start. And then now you own
a real estate brokerage. How does that process look like
once you're an agent trying to then move forward?
How does that process move up to own a
brokerage? That kind of transition? I know there's two
different licenses. Could you kind of break that down?
And how is that more specialized to you and
your process in doing that? So every agent has to
have a broker. You can't get in the real estate
business as a licensed agent without having a broker.
When I first got started, it was two years
and a certain amount of sales to get your
broker's license. So two years of experience as a sales
person. Literally right before I got to the two
year mark, they switched it to four. I'm like,
oh gosh, two more years.
So now it's four years. You have to have
a certain amount of transactions. There's a point system to
get up to, I believe, 900 points. Then
you have to have certain qualifications from real estate
classes. And college degree and the master's
degree satisfied all those credit hours. And I
had the amount of transactions needed, took the
test, got licensed. And then you become the one
that's responsible, that's on the hook, that
trains, that's there to support the agents.
And then there's a split structure.
We do 90-10. So agent, you close the deal, you
keep 90%, we take 10. My first brokerage, I was 50-50.
What is the hardest part
about owning a real estate brokerage?
One of the hardest parts is when you're trying
to lead the team. I've got challenges just like
everybody else, right? And you kind of got to not
worry about that and not let it show. So you've
got to be a leader when deals are
falling apart, when you got lawsuits, when you're getting
complaints, when you're getting a lot of complaints,
when you're getting a lot of complaints, when you're
getting complaints to track, and you got to show
up and still lead every day when you might be
battling with some stuff, which we are all the
time. And so separating the two is not something
that you can really do. You got to just
live through it and lead and show what's possible
and be there to support people. You are a
co-owner. You do have a partner, Alex, that we've
met and we're going to be interviewing him later.
What is it like working in that partnership? And
what are the qualities that you look
for when trying to find a business partner?
One in 20 partnerships work out, if that. Alex
and I grew up together. He doesn't talk about it
that often, so I have to do that for him
in some sense. But age 20 years old, full-blown heroin
addict and in jail. I mean, straight up. Not
somebody that I wanted to associate myself or be
around, right? Because when you're on heroin and
stuff like that, I mean, who knows what you're
doing? We started working together after he had gotten
sober. Still had my guard up a little bit.
I knew him since he was like
six years old, right? He's my brother's
best friend. Always a hustler, always making money. Just
got on this bad path for a little bit.
And what I would do is say, Alex, you want
to team up? Go knock on these doors. And I'd give
him 10 doors and he'd go knock 100. And I'd
say, hey, go call these people. He'd go call 10 times
the amount of people. So over two, three years,
we ended up having four or five properties that
we owned together. And then I realized this
guy's shaking that. He is stone cold sober,
up at 4 a.m., pray, meditate, work out.
He's extremely driven and sharp and realizes that
he has an opportunity to do something totally
different than where he was, which was working
at Firehouse Sub, riding his bike to work,
making minimum wage, literally living on pennies.
He knows how to live on pennies.
Wow. Straight up. So we teamed up and man,
it has been beautiful. We've divided the roles
where he's the operations guy. He counts the money.
He makes sure we're profitable. He hires
everybody. He fires someone if we have to.
And I'm out there living what I've been doing for
a long time. And I'm out there living what I've been
doing for a long time. And I'm out there living what
I've been doing for a long time. And I'm out there
living what I've been doing for a long time. And
I'm out there living what I've been doing for a long
time. And I'm out there living what I've been doing
for a long time. And I'm out there living what I
believe is my best role, which
is networking, building relationships, talking to people,
drumming up new ideas. So we operate our
business on a thing called traction. And he's the
implementer and I'm the visionary in a
sense. What's the best and worst financial decision
you've ever made, if you're comfortable sharing that?
And then also within that, what was your
biggest deal that you've done? I know that's a lot
of questions, but I'll take it. Tell me if I
missed one, but biggest
deal, $700,000, $780,000 wholesale fee.
Oh my God. So we made that at one time
between three partners. And it's great. It's a lot of
money. And for those of you that don't
know wholesaling, could you just explain that just
really quickly? Put a property under contract. The
lady hates brokers. Take off the broker hat.
We're investors. $2 million. We had a 3% commission
going to ourselves. And then we put it under
contract. We put up the earnest money and option
money, you know, 20 grand. We have control of this
piece of paper, which is actual ownership.
It's an ownership of the property. We started
calling builders, developers, everyone we could think of
to see if they were interested in this
property. It's nine and a half acres in Round
Rock. We're also sitting there like, we want to
buy this. We want to own this property. It's
a commercial property. Ended up getting an offer at
2.7. And it just, it wasn't real to me that
like we were going to make this money at closing. Like
I just didn't believe it. Closed it, made
the 700K, made the 3% commission, split it between
three partners, paid a huge tax on it. And then we
had to go to a different place. And we had to
go to a different place. And we had to go to
a different place. And we had to go to a different place.
Right. So it's not nearly as much as it seems,
but it was a really big deal. And we just transferred
the contract, utilize one skill set and one
tool of real estate. That was the biggest deal.
I do want to circle
back. Best and worst financial decisions.
Yeah. So, and then you also have properties.
I think we have maybe 130 properties. Worst
decision. And that is as of today is
cannabis stock. Wow. Down multiple million on it.
Do you know, was there like a specific?
One or was it just the industry in general?
In general, they're all down. But I have a company
called Acreage and I still believe in it. And I'm
really hoping, cause it's, that's been one of
my struggles, right? It's like that, that thing going
down. I don't talk about it often, but just
full disclosure. I mean, it goes down 60K, 100K, like
daily. Daily. Wow. And it's only been down. So
that's been very hard to deal with, but I believe
in the industry. I believe in that
company. They're doing $67 million last quarter in
revenue and the company's valued at 40 million.
So it's just, it's just, you know, we're just
early is how I view it. But I'm one
of the largest shareholders. No way. Yeah. I mean,
that's pretty cool. Yeah. It's pretty crazy.
So hopefully that works out, but that's been
very, very tough. And then best, best
decision was partnering with Alex by far. Partner,
finding the right partner to go try to accomplish
a very, very clear goal that we're very driven on.
Tell me the craziest real
estate story that you've ever heard.
You've experienced. The craziest thing I can think
of, it has to do with my wife
being pregnant and going to somebody's house on a
property that we manage and the lady coming out
and chasing her with a stick and her dog
and she's running around pregnant. You know, I mean,
that's like the craziest one. Cause that's just
bizarre. But the thing about it is every day,
there's something crazy. And then we just think
it's normal. We're like, yeah, you know, that was,
that was an interesting day. But when you
stop and think about it, you're like, wow,
we just met this guy at
an RV park and we walked around.
And sat down and had a beer and
negotiated the deal. I was just like, you know,
it just happened two weeks ago. Very spontaneous.
Yeah. I'm like, that's very unique. That's pretty
cool. So it's always something. Final question that I
do want to just wrap up with is, you know,
you are, you are, you know, fairly young. So what
do you see for the next 10 years for yourself
and what keeps you motivated to keep going?
I'm just driven, just like being around my mom,
I guess, you know, she was 24 seven. So a
lot of that wore off on me, but there's no other
path. I feel very, very blessed to have a
clear vision. Like we know where we're trying to go
and whether we do that or not. The one thing
I'll be proud of is to know that we tried
just having a clear goal. I'm a big believer that
you got to have goals in life. If you don't have
any kind of goal, like you can't be
happy, like something that you're pushing towards and making
progress to. And I'm not always, I'm not always
on fire, but for the most part, like, man, I'm,
I'm very clear on what we're trying to do. And
it gets proven every day by agents that are with us
that say, thank you.
This changed my life. And I mean, daily,
like really, really detailed and passionate text. And
so that is what keeps us going. That's amazing.
Well, that's going to wrap it up for 10 questions.
Thank you so much, Matt. If you want to just
real quick, how can people find your stuff? How can
they find your, your guys' profiles and maybe even
send you a DM, get started in real estate.
Easy, man. We're the easiest ever.
Every platform, TikTok, Instagram, Facebook, YouTube,
follow us. Matt Teifeke at Gmail,
teifekerealestate.com, cell phone number
512-914-4806. We're easy, man.
Two times.
Yeah. 512-914-4806.
He taught me that. Always
say the phone number two times.
I love that you said that, man. I always
do it too. I always do that, but yeah.
Absolutely. Well, Matt, it's been a pleasure. Thank
you much. Thank you so much for coming
on 10 questions. Guys, we're going to catch you
in the next one. We got a lot of great
videos dropping and, and yeah, we'll see you guys soon.